Flies. Chapter 12. Cry of the Hunters. Ralph lay in a covert,
wondering about his wounds. The bruised flesh was inches in diameter over his
bright ribs with a swollen and bloody scar where the spear had hit him. His
hair was full of dirt and tapped like the tendrils of a creeper. All over. He
was scratched and bruised from his flight through the forest. By the time
his breathing was normal again, he had worked out that bathing these injuries
would have to wait. How could you listen for naked feet if you were splashing in
water? How could you be safe by the little stream or on the open beach?
Ralph listened. He was not really far from the castle rock, and during the
first panic, he had thought he heard sounds of pursuit, but the hunters had
only sneaked into the fringes of the greenery, retrieving spears perhaps, and
then had rushed back to the sunny rock as if terrified of the darkness under
the leaves. He had even glimpsed one of them, striped brown, black, and red, and
had judged that it was Bill. But really thought Ralph, this was not Bill. This
was a savage whose image refused to blend with that ancient picture of a boy
in shorts and shirt. The afternoon died away. The circular spots of sunlight
moved steadily over green fronds and brown fiber, but no sound came from
behind the rock. At last Ralph wormed out of the ferns and sneaked forward to
the edge of that impenetrable thicket that fronted the neck of land. He peered
with elaborate caution between branches at the edge and could see Robert sitting
on guard at the top of the cliff. He held a spear in his left hand and was
tossing up a pebble and catching it again with the right. Behind him a
column of smoke rose thickly so that Ralph's nostrils flared and his mouth
dribbled. He wiped his nose and mouth with the back of his hand and for the
first time since the morning felt hungry. The tribe must be sitting around
the gutted pig, watching the fat ooze and burn among the ashes. They would be
intent. Another figure, an unrecognizable one, appeared by Robert
and gave him something, then turned and went back behind the rock. Robert laid
his spear on the rock beside him and began to gnaw between his raised hands.
So the feast was beginning, and the watchman had been given his portion.
Ralph saw that for the time being he was safe. He limped away through the fruit
trees, drawn by the thought of the poor food, yet bitter when he remembered the
feast. Feast today and then tomorrow. He argued unconvincingly that
they would let him alone, perhaps even make an outlaw of him. But then the
fatal, unreasoning knowledge came to him again. The breaking of the conchk and
the deaths of Piggy and Simon lay over the island like a vapor. These painted
savages would go further and further.
Then there was that indefinable connection between himself and Jack, who
therefore would never let him alone.
Never. He paused, sunflecked, holding up a bow, prepared to duck under it. A
spasm of terror set him shaking, and he cried aloud, "No, they're not as bad as
that. It was an accident." He ducked under the bow, ran clumsily, then
stopped and listened. He came to the smashed acres of fruit and ate greedily.
He saw two little onins and not having any idea of his own appearance wondered
why they screamed and ran. When he had eaten, he went toward the beach. The
sunlight was slanting now into the palms by the wrecked shelter. There was the
platform and the pool. The best thing to do was to ignore this leen feeling about
the heart and rely on their common sense, their daylight sanity. Now that
the tribe had eaten, the thing to do was to try again. And anyway, he couldn't
stay here all night in an empty shelter by the deserted platform. His flesh
crept and he shivered in the evening sun. No fire, no smoke, no rescue. He
turned and limped away through the forest toward Jack's end of the island.
The slanting sticks of sunlight were lost among the branches. At length he
came to a clearing in the forest, where rock prevented vegetation
from growing. Now it was a pool of shadows, and Ralph nearly flung himself
behind a tree when he saw something standing in the center. But then he saw
that the white face was bone and that the pig's skull grinned at him from the
top of his stick. He walked slowly into the middle of the clearing and looked
steadily at the skull that gleamed as white as ever the conchk had done and
seemed to jeer at him cynically. An inquisitive ant was busy in one of the
eye sockets, but otherwise the thing was lifeless. Or was it? Little prickles of
sensation ran up and down his back. He stood, the skull about on a level with
his face, and held up his hair with two hands. The teeth grinned. The empty
sockets seemed to hold his gaze masterfully and without effort. What was it?
The skull regarded Ralph like one who knows all the answers and won't tell. A
sick fear and rage swept him. Fiercely he hit out at the filthy thing in front
of him that bobbed like a toy and came back still grinning into his face so
that he lashed and cried out in loathing. Then he was licking his
bruised knuckles and looking at the bare stick while the skull lay in two pieces,
its grin now six feet across. He wrenched the quivering stick from the
crack and held it as a spear between him and the white pieces. Then he backed
away, keeping his face to the skull that lay grimming at the sky. When the green
glow had gone from the horizon and night was fully accomplished, Ralph came again
to the thicket in front of the castle rock. Peeping through, he could see that
the height was still occupied, and whoever it was up there had a spear at the
ready. He knelt among the shadows and felt his isolation bitterly. They were
savages, it was true, but they were human, and the ambushing fears of the
deep knight were coming on. Ralph moaned faintly, tired though he was, he could
not relax and fall into a well of sleep for fear of the tribe. Might it not be
possible to walk boldly into the fort, say, "I've got packs," laugh lightly,
and sleep among the others. Pretend they were still boys, school boys who had
said, "Sir, yes, sir," and worn caps.
Daylight might have answered yes, but darkness and the horrors of death said
no. Lying there in the darkness, he knew he was an outcast.
because I had some sense. He rubbed his cheek along his forearm, smelling the
acid scent of salt and sweat and the stailness of dirt. Over to the left, the
waves of ocean were breathing, sucking down, then boiling back over the rock.
There were sounds coming from behind the castle rock. Listening carefully,
detaching his mind from the swing of the sea, Ralph could make out a familiar
rhythm. Kill the beast. Cut his throat.
Spill his blood. The tribe was dancing.
Somewhere on the other side of this rocky wall, there would be a dark
circle, a glowing fire and meat. They would be savoring food and the comfort
of safety. A noise nearer at hand made him quiver. Savages were clambering up
the castle rock, right up to the top, and he could hear voices. He sneaked
forward a few yards and saw the shape at the top of the rock change and enlarge.
There were only two boys on the island who moved or talked like that. Ralph put
his head down on his forearms and accepted this new fact like a wound. Sam
and Eric were part of the tribe now.
They were guarding the castle rock against him. There was no chance of
rescuing them and building up an outlaw tribe at the other end of the island.
Sam and Eric were savages like the rest.
Piggy was dead, and the conchk smashed to powder. At length, the guard climbed
down. The two that remained seemed nothing more than a dark extension of
the rock. A star appeared behind them and was momentarily eclipsed by some
movement. Ralph edged forward, feeling his way over the uneven surface as
though he were blind. There were miles of vague water at his right, and the
restless ocean lay under his left hand as awful as the shaft of a pit. Every
minute the water breathed round the death rock and flowered into a field of
whiteness. Ralph crawled until he found the ledge of the entry in his grasp. The
lookouts were immediately above him, and he could see the end of a spear
projecting over the rock. He called very gently, "Sam and Eric!" There was no
reply. to carry. He must speak louder, and this would rouse those striped and
enimical creatures from their feasting by the fire. He set his teeth and
started to climb, finding the holds by touch. The stick that had supported a
skull hampered him, but he would not be parted from his only weapon. He was
nearly level with the twins before he spoke again. "Sam and Eric," he heard a
cry and a flurry from the rock. The twins had grabbed each other and were
gibbering. "It's me, Ralph." Terrified that they would run and give the alarm,
he hauled himself up until his head and shoulders stuck over the top. Far below
his armpit, he saw the luminous flowering round the rock. It's only me,
Ralph. At length, they bent forward and peered in his face. We thought it was We
didn't know what it was. We thought memory of their new and shameful loyalty
came to them. Eric was silent, but Sam tried to do his duty. You got to go,
Ralph. You go away now. He wagged his spear and assayed fierceness. You shove
off. See? Eric nodded agreement and jabbed his spear in the air. Ralph
leaned on his arms and did not go. I came to see you two. His voice was
thick. His throat was hurting him now, though it had received no wound. I came
to see you two. Words could not express the dull pain of these things. He fell
silent while the vivid stars were split and danced all ways. Sam shifted
uneasily. Honest, Ralph, you'd better go. Ralph looked up again. You two
aren't painted. How can you? If it were light, if it were light, shame would
burn them at admitting these things. But the night was dark. Eric took up, and
then the twins started their antipal speech. You got to go because it's not
safe. They made us. They heard us. Who, Jack? Oh, no. They bent to him and lowered their
voices. Push off, Ralph. It's a tribe.
They made us. We couldn't help it. When Ralph spoke again, his voice was low and
seemed breathless. What have I done? I liked him and I wanted us to be rescued
again. The stars spilled about the sky.
Eric shook his head earnestly. Listen, Ralph, never mind what sense. That's
gone. Never mind about the chief. You got to go for your own good. The chief
and Roger. Yes, Roger. They hate you, Ralph. They're going to do you. They're
going to hunt you tomorrow. But why? I don't know. And Ralph, Jack, the chief
says it'll be dangerous. And we've got to be careful and throw our spears like
at a pig. We're going to spread out in a line across the island. We're going
forward from this end until we find you.
We've got to give signals like this.
Eric raised his head and achieved a faint ugulation by beating on his open
mouth. Then he glanced behind him nervously. Like that, only louder, of
course. But I've done nothing, whispered Ralph urgently. I only wanted to keep up
a fire. He paused for a moment, thinking miserably of the tomorrow. A matter of
overwhelming importance occurred to him.
What are you? He could not bring himself to be specific at first, but then fear
and loneliness goed him. When they find me, what are they going to do? The twins
were silent. Beneath him, the death rock flowered again. What are they? Oh god,
I'm hungry. The towering rock seemed to sway under him. Well,
what? The twins answered his question indirectly. You got to go now, Ralph.
For your own good. Keep away as far as you can. Won't you come with me? three
of us, we'd stand a chance." After a moment's silence, Sam spoke in a
strangled voice. "You don't know Roger.
He's a terror." "And the chief, they're both terrors. Only Roger." Both boys
froze. Someone was climbing toward them from the tribe. "He's coming to see if
we're keeping watch. Quick, Ralph," as he prepared to let himself down the
cliff. Ralph snatched at the last possible advantage to be rung out of
this meeting. "He'll lie up close in that thicket down there," he whispered.
"So keep them away from it. They'll never think to look so close." The
footsteps were still some distance away.
Sam, I'm going to be all right, aren't I? The twins were silent again. Here,
said Sam suddenly. Take this. Ralph felt a chunk of meat pushed against him and
grabbed it. But what are you going to do when you catch me? Silence above. He
sounded silly to himself. He lowered himself down the rock. What are you
going to do? From the top of the towering rock came the incomprehensible
reply. Roger sharpened a stick at both ends. Roger sharpened a stick at both
ends. Ralph tried to attach a meaning to this, but could not. He used all the bad
words he could think of in a fit of temper that passed into yawning. How
long could you go without sleep? He yearned for a bed and sheets, but the
only whiteness here was the slow spilt milk, luminous round the rock 40 ft
below where Piggy had fallen. Piggy was everywhere, was on this neck, was become
terrible in darkness and death. If Piggy were to come back now out of the water
with his empty head, Ralph whimpered and yawned like a little. The stick in his hand became a
crutch on which he reeled. Then he tensed again. There were voices raised
on the top of the castle rock. Sam and Eric were arguing with someone, but the
ferns and the grass were near. That was the place to be in, hidden, and next to
the thicket that would serve for tomorrow's hideout. here and his hands
touched grass was a place to be in for the night, not far from the tribe, so
that if the horrors of the supernatural emerged, one could at least mix with
humans for the time being, even if it meant What did it mean? A stick
sharpened at both ends. What was there in that? They had thrown spears and
missed all but one. Perhaps they would miss next time, too. He squatted down in
the tall grass, remembered the meat that Sam had given him, and began to tear at
it ravenously. While he was eating, he heard fresh noises, cries of pain from
Sam and Eric, cries of panic, angry voices. What did it mean? Someone
besides himself was in trouble, for at least one of the twins was catching it.
Then the voices passed away down the rock, and he ceased to think of them. He
felt with his hands and found cool, delicate fronds backed against the
thicket. Here then was the knight's lair. At first light, he would creep
into the thicket, squeeze between the twisted stems, and sconce himself so
deep that only a crawler like himself could come through, and that crawler
would be jabbed. There he would sit and the search would pass him by and the
cordon waver on uulating along the island and he would be free. He pulled
himself between the ferns tunneling in.
He laid the stick beside him and huddled himself down in the blackness. One must
remember to wake at first light in order to diddle the savages, and he did not
know how quickly sleep came and hurled him down a dark interior
slope. He was awake before his eyes were open, listening to a noise that was
near. He opened an eye, found the mold an inch or so from his face, and his
fingers gripped into it, light filtering between the fronds of fern. He had just
time to realized that the age-ong nightmares of falling and death were
passed, and that the morning was come when he heard the sound again. It was an
unulation over by the seashore, and now the next savage answered, and the
next. The cry swept by him across the narrow end of the island from sea to
lagoon, like the cry of a flying bird.
He took no time to consider, but grabbed his sharp stick and wriggled back among
the ferns. Within seconds, he was worming his way into the thicket, but
not before he had glimpsed the legs of a savage coming toward him. The ferns were
thumped and beaten, and he heard legs moving in the long grass. The savage,
whoever he was, utilated twice, and the cry was repeated in both directions,
then died away. Ralph crouched still, tangled in the ferns, and for a time he heard
nothing. At last he examined the thicket itself. Certainly, no one could attack
him here, and moreover he had a stroke of luck. The great rock that had killed
Piggy had bounded into this thicket and bounced there right in the center,
making a smashed space a few feet in extent each way. When Ralph had wriggled
into this, he felt secure and clever. He sat down carefully among the smashed
stems and waited for the hunt to pass.
Looking up between the leaves, he caught a glimpse of something red. That must be
the top of the castle rock, distant and unmenacing. He composed himself
triumphantly to hear the sounds of the hunt dying away. Yet no one made a
sound, and as the minutes passed in the green shade, his feeling of triumph
faded. At last he heard a voice, Jack's voice, but hushed. Are you certain? The
savage addressed said nothing. Perhaps he made a gesture. Roger spoke. If
you're fooling us. Immediately after this, there came a gasp and a squeal of
pain. Ralph crouched instinctively. One of the twins was there outside the
thicket with Jack and Roger. You're sure he meant in there? The twin moaned
faintly and then squealled again. He meant he'd hide in there. Yes. Yes. So
silver laughter scattered among the trees. So they knew. Ralph picked up his
stick and prepared for battle. But what could they
do? It would take them a week to break a path through the thicket, and anyone who
wormed his way in would be helpless. He felt the point of his spear with his
thumb and grinned without amusement.
Whoever tried that would be stuck, squealing like a pig. They were going
away back to the tower rock. He could hear feet moving, and then someone
sniggered. There came again that high bird-like cry that swept along the line.
So some were still watching for him, but some There was a long, breathless
silence. Ralph found that he had bark in his mouth from the nod spear. He stood
and peered upwards to the castle rock.
As he did so, he heard Jack's voice from the top. Heave, heave, heave. The red
rock that he could see at the top of the cliff vanished like a curtain, and he
could see figures and blue sky. A moment later, the earth jolted. There was a
rushing sound in the air, and the top of the thicket was cuffed as with a
gigantic hand. The rock bounded on, thumping and smashing toward the beach
while a shower of broken twigs and leaves fell on him. Beyond the thicket,
the tribe was cheering. Silence again.
Ralph put his fingers in his mouth and bit them. There was only one other rock
up there that they might conceivably move, but that was half as big as a
cottage, big as a car, a tank. He visualized its probable progress with
agonizing clearness. That one would start slowly, drop from ledge to ledge,
trundle across the neck like an outside steamroller. Heave. Heave. cave. Ralph
put down his spear, then picked it up again. He pushed his hair back
irritably, took two hasty steps across the little space, and then came back. He
stood looking at the broken ends of branches. Still silence. He caught sight of the rise and
fall of his diaphragm and was surprised to see how quickly he was breathing.
Just left of center, his heartbeats were visible. He put the spear down again.
Heave, heave, heave. A shrill prolonged cheer. Something boomed up on the red rock.
Then the earth jumped and began to shake steadily while the noise as steadily
increased. Ralph was shot into the air, thrown down, dashed against branches. At
his right hand, and only a few feet away, the whole thicket bent, and the
roots screamed as they came out of the earth together. He saw something red
that turned over slowly as a millheel.
Then the red thing was passed, and the elephantine progress diminished toward
the sea. Ralph knelt on the plowed up soil and waited for the earth to come
back. Presently the white broken stumps, the split sticks, and the tangle of the
thicket refocused. There was a kind of heavy feeling in his body where he had
watched his own pulse. Silence again, yet not entirely so. They were
whispering out there, and suddenly the branches were shaken furiously at two
places on his right. The pointed end of a stick appeared. In panic, Ralph thrust
his own stick through the crack and struck with all his might. Ah! His spear
twisted a little in his hands, and then he withdrew again. "Oh! Oh, someone was
moaning outside and a babble of voices rose. A fierce argument was going on and
the wounded savage kept groaning. Then, when there was silence, a single voice
spoke, and Ralph decided that it was not Jax. See, I told you he's dangerous. The
wounded savage moaned again. What else?
What next? Ralph fastened his hands round the chewed spear, and his hair
fell. Someone was muttering only a few yards away toward the castle rock. He
heard a savage say, "No!" in a shocked voice, and then there was suppressed
laughter. He squatted back on his heels and showed his teeth at the wall of
branches. He raised his spear, snarled a little, and waited. Once more, the
invisible group sniggered. He heard a curious trickling sound, and then a
louder crepitation as if someone were unwrapping great sheets of cellophane. A
stick snapped, and he stifled a cough.
Smoke was seeping through the branches in white and yellow wisps. The patch of
blue sky overhead turned to the color of a storm cloud, and then the smoke billowed around
him. Someone laughed excitedly, and a voice shouted, "Smoke!" He wormed his
way through the thicket toward the forest, keeping as far as possible
beneath the smoke. Presently he saw open space in the green leaves of the edge of
the thicket. A smalish savage was standing between him and the rest of the
forest. A savage striped red and white and carrying a spear. He was coughing
and smearing the paint about his eyes with the back of his hand as he tried to
see through the increasing smoke. Ralph launched himself like a cat, stabbed,
snarling with a spear, and the savage doubled up. There was a shout from
beyond the thicket, and then Ralph was running with the swiftness of fear through the
undergrowth. He came to a pig run, followed it for perhaps a hundred yards,
and then swerved off. Behind him the uulation swept across the island once
more, and a single voice chattered three times. He guessed that was the signal to
advance, and sped away again, till his chest was like fire. Then he flung
himself down under a bush, and waited for a moment till his breathing
steadied. He passed his tongue tentatively over his teeth and lips, and
heard far off the uulation of the pursuers.
There were many things he could do. He could climb a tree, but that was putting
all his eggs in one basket. If he were detected, they had nothing more
difficult to do than wait. If only one had time to think. Another double cry at
the same distance gave him a clue to their plan. Any savage bulked in the
forest would utter the double shout and hold up the line till he was free again.
That way they might hope to keep the cordon unbroken right across the island.
Ralph thought of the boar that had been broken through them with such ease. If
necessary, when the chase came too close, he could charge the cordon while
it was still thin, burst through, and run back. But run back where? The cordon
would turn and sweep again. Sooner or later, he would have to sleep or eat,
and then he would awaken with hands clawing at him, and the hunt would
become a running down. What was to be done, then? The tree burst the line like
a boar? Either way, the choice was terrible.
A single cry quickened his heartbeat, and leaping up he dashed away toward the
oceanside and the thick jungle till he was hung up among creepers. He stayed
there for a moment with his calves quivering, if only one could have quiet,
a long pause and time to think. And there again, shrill and inevitable, was
the utilation sweeping across the island. At that sound he shied like a
horse among the creepers, and ran once more till he was panting.
He flung himself down by some ferns. The tree or the charge, he mastered his
breathing for a moment, wiped his mouth, and told himself to be calm. Sam and
Eric were somewhere in that line, and hating it. Or were they? And supposing
instead of them he met the chief, or Roger, who carried death in his hands.
Ralph pushed back his tangled hair and wiped the sweat out of his best eye, he
spoke aloud. Think. What was the sensible thing to do? There was no piggy
to talk sense. There was no solemn assembly for debate, nor dignity of the
conchk. Think. most he was beginning to dread the curtain that might waver in
his brain, blacking out the sense of danger, making a simpleton of him. A
third idea would be to hide so well that the advancing line would pass without
discovering him. He jerked his head off the ground and listened. There was
another noise to attend to now, a deep grumbling noise, as though the forest
itself were angry with him, a somber noise across which the utilations were
scribbled excruciatingly on as on slate. He knew he had heard it somewhere
before, but had no time to remember.
Break the line, a tree. Hide and let them pass. A nearer cry stood him on his
feet, and immediately he was away again, running fast among thorns and brambles.
Suddenly he blundered into the open, found himself again in that open space,
and there was the fathom wide grin of the skull, no longer ridiculing a deep
blue patch of sky, but jeering up into a blanket of smoke. Then Ralph was running
beneath trees with the grumble of the forest explained. They had smoked him
out and set the island on fire.
Hide was better than a tree because you had a chance of breaking the line if you
were discovered. Hide then. He wondered if a pig would agree and grimaced at
nothing. Find the deepest thicket, the darkest hole on the island and creep
in. Now, as he ran, he peered about him.
Bars and splashes of sunlight flitted over him, and sweat made glistening
streaks on his dirty body. The cries were far now and faint. At last he found
what seemed to him the right place, though the decision was desperate. Here,
bushes and a wild tangle of creeper made a mat that kept out all the light of the
sun. Beneath it was a space perhaps a foot high, though it was pierced
everywhere by parallel and rising stems.
If you wormed into the middle of that, you would be 5 yards from the edge and
hidden, unless the savage chose to lie down and look for you. And even then you
would be in darkness. And if the worst happened and he saw you, then you had a
chance to burst out at him, fling the whole line out of step, and double back.
Cautiously, his stick trailing behind him, Ralph wormed between the rising
stems. When he reached the middle of the mat, he lay and listened. The fire was a
big one, and the drum roll that he had thought was left so far behind was
nearer. Couldn't a fire outrun a galloping horse? He could see the sun
splashed ground over an area perhaps 50 yards from where he lay. And as he
watched, the sunlight in every patch blinked at him. This was so like the
curtain that flapped in his brain, that for a moment he thought the blinking was
inside him. But then the patches blinked more rapidly, dulled, and went out, so
that he saw that a great heaviness of smoke lay between the island and the
sun. If anyone peered under the bushes and chanced to glimpse human flesh, it
might be Sam and Eric who would pretend not to see and say nothing. He laid his
cheek against the chocolatecovered earth, licked his dry lips, and closed
his eyes. Under the thicket, the earth was vibrating very slightly. Or perhaps
there was a sound beneath the obvious thunder of the fire and scribbled
utilations that was too low to hear.
Someone cried out. Ralph jerked his cheek off the earth and looked into the
dulled light. "They must be near now," he thought, and his chest began to
thump. hide, break the line, climb a tree, which was the best after all. The
trouble was, you only had one chance.
Now the fire was nearer. Those voling shots were great limbs, trunks even,
bursting. The fools. The fools. The fire must be almost at the fruit trees. What
would they eat tomorrow? Ralph stirred restlessly in his narrow bed. One
chance, nothing. What could they do?
Beat him? So what? Kill him? A stick sharpened at both ends. The cries,
suddenly nearer, jerked him up. He could see a striped savage moving hastily out
of a green tangle and coming toward the mat where he hid. A savage who carried a
spear. Ralph gripped his fingers into the earth. Be ready now in case. Ralph
fumbled to hold his spear so that it was point foremost. And now he saw that the
stick was sharpened at both ends. The savage stopped 15 yards away and uttered
his cry. Perhaps he can hear my heart over the noises of the fire. Don't
scream. Get ready. The savage moved forward so that you could only see him
from the waist down. That was the butt of his spear. Now you could see him from
the knee down. Don't scream. A herd of pigs came squealing out of the greenery
behind the savage and rushed away into the forest. Birds were screaming, mice
shrieking, and a little hopping thing came under the mat and cowed. 5 yards
away, the savage stopped, standing right by the thicket and cried out. Ralph drew
his feet up and crouched. The steak was in his hands, the stake sharpened at
both ends. The stake that vibrated so wildly that grew long, short, light,
heavy, light again. The utilation spread from shore to shore. The savage knelt
down by the edge of the thicket, and there were lights flickering in the
forest behind him. You could see a knee disturbed the mold. Now the other, two
hands, a spear, a face. The savage peered into the obscurity beneath the
thicket. You could tell that he saw light on this side and on that, but not
in the middle. There. In the middle was a blob of dark, and the savage wrinkled
up his face, trying to decipher the darkness. The seconds lengthened. Ralph
was looking straight into the savage's eyes. Don't scream. You'll get back. Now
he's seen you. He's making sure. A stick sharpened. Ralph screamed. A scream of
fright and anger and desperation. His legs straightened. The screams became
continuous and foaming. He shot forward, burst the thicket, was in the open,
screaming, snarling, bloody. He swung the stake, and the savage tumbled over.
But there were others coming toward him, crying out. He swerved as the spear flew
past and then was silent, running. All at once, the lights flickering ahead of
him merged together. The roar of the forest rose to thunder, and a tall bush
directly in his path burst into a great fan-shaped flame. He swung to the right,
running desperately fast, with the heat beating on his left side, and the fire
racing forward like a tide. The unulation rose behind him and spread
along. A series of short, sharp cries, the sighting call. A brown figure showed
up at his right and fell away. They were all running, all crying out madly. He
could hear them crashing in the undergrowth, and on the left was the
hot, bright thunder of the fire. He forgot his wounds, his hunger and
thirst, and became fear. Hopeless fear on flying feet, rushing through the
forest toward the open beach. Spots jumped before his eyes and turned into
red circles that expanded quickly till they passed out of sight. Below him, someone's legs were
getting tired, and the desperate uulation advanced like a jagged fringe
of menace and was almost overhead. He stumbled over a route, and the cry that
pursued him rose even higher. He saw a shelter burst into flames, and the fire
flapped at his right shoulder, and there was the glitter of water. Then he was
down, rolling over and over in the warm sand, crouching with arm to ward off,
trying to cry for mercy. He staggered to his feet, tensed
for more terrors, and looked up at a huge peaked cap. It was a white to cap,
and above the green shade of the peak was a crown, an anchor, gold foliage. He
saw white drill, epolettes, a revolver, a row of guilt buttons down the front of
a uniform. A naval officer stood on the sand. Looking down at Ralph in wary
astonishment. On the beach behind him was a cutter, her bows hauled up and
held by two ratings. In the stern sheets, another rating held a submachine
gun. The utilation faltered and died away. The officer looked at Ralph
doubtfully for a moment, then took his hand away from the butt of the revolver.
Hello. Squirming a little, conscious of his filthy appearance, Ralph answered
shily. Hello. The officer nodded as if a question had been answered. Are there
any adults? Any grown-ups with you?
Dumbly, Ralph shook his head. He turned a halfpace on the sand. A semicircle of
little boys, their bodies stre with colored clay, sharp sticks in their
hands, were standing on the beach, making no noise at all. "Fun and games,"
said the officer. The fire reached the coconut palms by the beach and swallowed
them noisily. A flame, seemingly detached, swung like an acrobat and
licked up the palm heads on the platform. The sky was black. The officer
grinned cheerfully at Ralph. "We saw your smoke. What have you been doing?
Having a war or something?" Ralph nodded. The officer inspected the little
scarecrow in front of him. The kid needed a bath, a haircut, a nose wipe,
and a good deal of ointment. Nobody killed, I hope. Any dead bodies? Only two, and they've
gone. The officer leaned down and looked closely at Ralph. Two killed? Ralph
nodded again. Behind him, the whole island was shuddering with flame. The
officer knew, as a rule, when people were telling the truth. He whistled
softly. Other boys were appearing now.
Tiny tots, some of them. brown with the distended bellies of small savages. One
of them came close to the officer and looked up. I'm I'm But there was no more
to come. Perl Weis Madison sought in his head for an incantation that had faded
clean away. The officer turned back to Ralph. Well take you off. How many
of you are there? Ralph shook his head.
The officer looked past him to the group of painted boys. Who's boss here? I am,
said Ralph loudly. A little boy who wore the remains of an extraordinary black
cap on his red hair, and who carried the remains of a pair of spectacles at his
waist, started forward, then changed his mind, and stood still. "We saw your
smoke, and you don't know how many of you there are?" "No, sir." "I should
have thought," said the officer, as he visualized the search before him. "I
should have thought that a pack of British boys, you're all British, aren't
you, would have been able to put up a better show than that. I mean, it was
like that at first," said Ralph, "before things He stopped. We were together
then. The officer nodded helpfully. I know. Jolly good show. Like the coral
island. Ralph looked at him dumbly. For a moment he had a fleeting picture of
the strange glamour that had once invested the beaches, but the island was
scorched up like dead wood. Simon was dead, and Jack had the tears began to
flow, and sobs shook him. He gave himself up to them now for the first
time on the island. great shuddering spasms of grief that seemed to wrench
his whole body. His voice rose under the black smoke before the burning wreckage
of the island. And infected by that emotion, the other little boys began to shake and sob,
too. And in the middle of them, with filthy body, matted hair, and unwiped
nose, Ralph wept for the end of innocence, the darkness of man's heart,
and the fall through the air of the true wise friend called Piggy. The officer,
surrounded by these noises, was moved and a little embarrassed. He turned away
to give them time to pull themselves together and waited, allowing his eyes
to rest on the trim cruiser in the